Wanting to learn is not the same as getting started, seeing how ideas fit together, or finishing.
StartOne turns one uploaded source into one clear first step, a visual knowledge map, and a focused learning loop that keeps moving one concept at a time.
The learner uploads a PDF, Markdown or text file, or pastes notes.
Uploaded material is required and remains the primary source.
Parsing results stay inside the upload panel, with real page or line locations.
One button lets AI choose a learning focus, connect the concepts, and prepare the first explanation.
There is no setup form and no pre-test.
GPT-5.6 returns schema-validated coverage and a connected dependency map.
Every node is clickable, so the learner can see what a concept means and where it belongs without changing the route.
One clear action opens a beginner-friendly explanation: the big idea, its place in the framework, key parts, a concrete example, and one memory anchor.
If the learner gets stuck, the contextual Tutor explains and asks smaller questions, but only for the active concept.
A three-question quiz or one free-recall response then creates active retrieval.
Hints, immediate feedback, specific encouragement, and targeted remediation all stay inside the Guided Mastery Loop.
Quiz feedback is intentionally small: the score, each answer, why it is correct, and one truthful win.
Behind the interface, the loop records factual LearningEvidence with no recommendation.
Keep going asks the planning Agent for exactly one bounded action and automatically enters the next safe learning task, avoiding another decision screen.
External search is impossible until four gates pass: the session permits search suggestions, the server validates a named material gap, the Agent requests search, and the learner confirms this exact scope.
Only that confirmed execution receives the web-search tool.
Cited results are clearly labeled as external supplements; uploaded material always remains primary.
Autosave, conflict-safe drafts, pause and exact resume make interruption recoverable.
Lightweight source citations preserve trust without distracting from learning.
The interface is English, responsive, keyboard-oriented, and uses calm, flat backgrounds with one visually dominant action.
Codex transformed the product specification, prototype, and acceptance cases into this tested FastAPI application, while I set the learning boundaries and corrected issues found through browser review.
GPT-5.6 powers the public structured map, explanations, Tutor, practice, feedback, and bounded planning flow.
Deterministic fixtures remain isolated to automated tests.